Azamat Sarkytbayev

□ a.sarkytbayev@gmail.com LinkedIn: asarkytbayev

Qualification Summary:

Self-motivated young professional with programming, industrial and teaching experience. Currently studying MS Computer Science Align at Northeastern University. Completed an internship at the Bristol Robotics Lab. Worked as factory operator and as a teaching assistant.

Technical Skills:

- C/C++. Java
- OOP, CUnit/JUnit testing

Professional Experience:

Northeastern University: Teaching Assistant

May 2018 - present

San Jose, US

Assist teaching OO Design, Algorithms and Computer Systems classes

Northeastern University: Align Ambassador

Oct 2017 - April 2018

San Jose, US

• Served as a link between current students and administration. I planned social events and was available for students to go to with questions or concerns.

Bristol Robotics Laboratory: Internship

Oct 2016 - Dec 2016

Bristol, UK

• Optimized the existing Arduino code for smoother operation of pneumatic grippers and profile driven units

Nazarbayev University: Teaching Assistant

Aug 2014 – Jul 2015

Astana, Kazakhstan

 Supported the delivery of teaching by running tutorial and laboratory sessions for over 100 students in the department of Mechanical engineering

Astana Solar: Production Line Operator

Oct 2013 - Aug 2014

Astana, Kazakhstan

 Increased maximum production output by 10% to reach 232 panels per shift, by participating in planning and execution of a more efficient manufacturing strategy

Education:

Northeastern University MS Computer Science Align

Sep 2017 - Present

San Jose, US

Current courses: Fundamentals of CS, Data Structures, Object Orient Design,

Computer Systems, Algorithms

Bristol University & UWE

MSc Robotics

Sep 2015 - Sep 2016

Bristol, UK

GPA 3.7

Dissertation: Successfully developed and tested a robotic end-effector, with an array of vacuum gripping modules for carbon fibre handling, mounted on an industrial robot arm Projects:

- Developed a finite state machine for simulated UAV cloud tracking in MATLAB
- Calculated the inverse kinematics of a robot arm in MATLAB by employing an analytical method, creating an adaptive neuro-fuzzy network inference system and neural network

University College London

BS Math & Physics

Oct 2010 - May 2013

London, UK

GPA 3.3

IB: 39/45

Sep 2005 - May 2010

Hertfordshire, UK **IGCSE:** 5A*, 4A

Additional Information:

Haileybury & ISC

• Fluent written and spoken Kazakh, Russian